KLIGAN BRAGANZA

9 Noel Court Hounslow, Middlesex TW4 - 7DD 07404752738

Email - <u>Kliganbraganza@gmail.com</u> Website - <u>www.kliganbraganza.co.uk</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

Solution driven Front-End developer passionate about building responsive websites and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 4+ years. Proven experience developing consumer focused websites using HTML/CSS, JS frameworks, php and node.js. Developed web applications over multiple API's, third party integrations and databases. Notable achievements include live mobile applications and games with over 1 million installs worldwide.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Languages	Framework	JS Libraries
 Java JavaScript TypeScript HTML/CSS3 C# PHP .NET 	React.jsReact NativeNode.jsExpress.jsjQueryBootstrap	Chart.jsThree.jsParallax.jsPixie.js
Node.js Libraries Nodemailer Axios	Storage MySQL MongoDB	Tools/TechnologiesAndroid StudioWordpress
CorsNodemonCheerioBody-parser	Google Firebase	 GraphQL Ajax JSON Gatsby Git

EXPERIENCE

May 2016 - Sept 2019 "Freelance Mobile and Web developer" (London, UK)

- Modified designs and specifications of complex applications with the help of JavaScript.
- Wrote, modified, and debugged web applications using Node.js, JavaScript, php, HTML5 and CSS3
- Developed client-side single-page applications using modern frameworks like React and libraries like Parallax.js
- Worked on RESTful API designs along with AJAX and Axios API calls.
- Deployed applications and hosted websites using platforms such as Heroku and Netlify.
- Created web content, web graphics and multimedia for client websites using CMS such as Contentful and Wordpress.

Aug 2014 - Feb 2016 "Software Developer " (Hyderabad, India) Sruthika Entertainment Pvt Ltd

- Developed user interface elements for Web-based applications based on program specifications.
- Debugging and optimization of code.
- Worked with third-party JavaScript and C# libraries and APIs
- Worked with other developers, designers and product/business managers to develop new features.
- Identify and troubleshoot issues with frameworks and component libraries;
 assist development teams with use of the frameworks and libraries
- Work with various Android development frameworks and continuous integration frameworks such as GIT, HockeyApp & Android Studio

Notable achievements include Android Mobile game 'Zombie Little' with over 100k installs worldwide.

July 2017 - Present "Customer Executive" (London, UK)

Menzies Aviation (part –time)

- Operate computers, air-bridge, scanners and airline specific software.
- Produce work-related documentation when required
- Issue boarding passes and passenger check-in
- Trace and track customer freight

Sept 2016 - June 2017 "Tax Consultant" (London, UK)

Travelex UK Pvt Ltd

- Used database systems to track generated leads.
- Organize the company's tax database
- Provided advice on the most suitable IT choices
- Foreign Exchange
- Using software to calculate vat tax refunds

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS

- Oct 2019 Present JustIT training and recruitment, (London, UK)
 Web Development Immersive (Bootcamp)
- Mar 2019 May 2019
 London Training Group Ltd, (London, UK)
 Web Development and UX design (Bootcamp)
- July 2014 June 2015
 Image College of Arts and Technology, (Bangalore, India)
 Post-Graduation diploma in Game Development
- June 2009 May 2014
 Rayeshwar Institute of Technology, Goa University (Goa, India)
 Bachelor Degree in Information Technology (BTech IT)
- June 2006 Mar 2009
 St Xaviers College
 GCSE Math's, English, Science (AAB)

INTERESTS

- Playing Chess and Online Multiplayer Gaming
- Digital Designing using Photoshop, 3D software's such as maya
- Coding

Personal Projects

1. Health Website build using JavaScript

This Interactive health Website is build using pure vanilla JavaScript and it helps users to exercise from home and complete health miles. The Home page is developed using JavaScript Library Parallax.js for the movement effect.

2. JavaScript and Node.js website

This fitness website has complete details about different types of workouts.